<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Folissimo Blog</title><link href="http://blog.folissimo.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.folissimo.com/feeds/tips.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.folissimo.com/</id><updated>2013-02-07T09:30:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Why you should consider a splash screen</title><link href="http://blog.folissimo.com/why-splash-screens.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-07T09:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Campbell Morgan</name></author><id>tag:blog.folissimo.com,2013-02-07:why-splash-screens.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Splash Screens are a great way of introducing your website and is available as an option for all Folissimo themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try out a splash screen for your site:
&lt;em&gt; click on the "Customise Theme" button to open the Theme Editor
&lt;/em&gt; tick the 'splash' box on the top right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to customise the position and colour of your splash screen, click on the new tab "Splash" at the top then edit the available options.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Tips"></category><category term="Using Folissimo"></category><category term="Splash"></category></entry><entry><title>How favicons can personalise your site</title><link href="http://blog.folissimo.com/logo-and-favicon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-06T09:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Campbell Morgan</name></author><id>tag:blog.folissimo.com,2013-02-06:logo-and-favicon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Favicons are the tiny icons that appear in the browser tab when you're viewing your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend that you upload your own because this will make your site stand out in people's history and bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default is the Folissimo logo, but you can upload your own image within the "preferences":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on "preferences", then click on the "logo" tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select "upload your own favicon"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose any image, but if you upload an image which is 16x16 pixels it'll be really sharp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="Tips"></category><category term="Using Folissimo"></category><category term="Adding a favicon"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting your Fonts Right</title><link href="http://blog.folissimo.com/getting-your-fonts-right.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Campbell Morgan</name></author><id>tag:blog.folissimo.com,2013-01-18:getting-your-fonts-right.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Typography is immensely important to the clarity and presentation of your content. If you’re not used to thinking about fonts, here are some tips to help improve style and readability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep it simple: if you’re planning to use more than 2 fonts, make sure you’re confidently going for a particular style because a lot of fonts can make a site messy and hard to navigate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vary headings &amp;amp; body text: make sure there is a clear difference between headings and the body of your text. This can be achieved in a number of ways:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternate between a serif font (eg Times, Garamond, Georgia etc) and a sans-serif font (Arial, Helvetica, Tahoma etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt; bold &lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; to emphasise differences: eg set a heading in bold, then the body in italic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put headings in UPPERCASE to contrast with the body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take control of font sizes by making the heading much larger than the body text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure body text is legible: complex fonts can be great for very large header fonts, but can often be very difficult to read at normal text size. Make sure you use clear, well-spaced fonts whenever you want your audience to read more than a sentence of text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep an eye on current trends: every time you see some typography that you like, ask yourself why you like it and look at the details. Is it a nice font or a nice combination of fonts? Trends change fast, so you need to pay attention to keep up-to-date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Customising your fonts on Folissimo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each theme on Folissimo has a range of curated fonts, selected by the Folissimo team. If however, you would something more personal, then choose the “custom font” option from the fonts menu in the “Theme Editor” and then click “edit”. You will then be able to change the font, size, style and weight for your heading, menu and body text.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Tips"></category><category term="Typography"></category><category term="Admin"></category></entry><entry><title>Tracking your Users with Google Analytics</title><link href="http://blog.folissimo.com/track-with-google-analytics.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-17T09:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Campbell Morgan</name></author><id>tag:blog.folissimo.com,2013-01-17:track-with-google-analytics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Knowing what your audience wants is really important to building and maintaining a successful website. You may think that you have a good idea what your most impressive work is, but you never know until you see the stats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to see detailed information on who visits your site, where they come from, how long they stay on your site and a whole host of other information, then we highly recommend you link Google Analytics to your Folissimo page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How to do it:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an account at &lt;a href="www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;www.google.com/analytics/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new property using your Folissimo address (ie www.yoursite.com or yoursite.folissimo.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your new property will have an id - something like UA-XXXXXXXX-X where X is a number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to the admin section (admin.folissimo.com) and click on “Preferences” then click on the “Search” tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paste your property id into the “Google Analytics” field and press save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within 24 hours Google Analytics you will start getting detailed information on your site&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Tips"></category><category term="Using Folissimo"></category><category term="Google Analytics"></category></entry><entry><title>Understanding Search Engines</title><link href="http://blog.folissimo.com/understanding-search-engines.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-16T13:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Campbell Morgan</name></author><id>tag:blog.folissimo.com,2013-01-16:understanding-search-engines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you search for your name or business, you may be lucky enough to occupy the top spot at google, but if you’re not, you might be frustrated, wondering why whoever has made it to the top deserves that place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand why, It helps to understand how Google and other major search engines (such as Microsoft’s Bing) rank their pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to say is that the precise details of how each search engine categorises content is a &lt;em&gt;commercial secret&lt;/em&gt; to ensure that nobody is able to successfully “game” the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, having a rough idea of how it works should help your page rank. At its simplest, search engines gauge both the quality and relevance of the results using a combination of the content on your page, the “meta description” (more on that later) and most importantly, the pages which link through to your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tips:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that you describe your work accurately and concisely using words that people are likely to search for eg: “John Smith, a North London sculptor working primarily with copper and found objects” is much better than “John Smith, artist working with 3d”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a concise “meta description”  (found under the “search” tab in the preferences) describing your site in less than 30-40 words. The meta description is some text which is included in every one of your pages, but is only visible to computers. Google usually use this to form the description of your page in their results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage as many people as possible to link to your site every time they mention you online, but make sure that the links are used relevantly rather than haphazardly: if google sense that you are paying people to link to your site, they will ban you!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try and get your site linked from sites which are well-respected and from sites with a lot of traffic : being linked from the Tate Gallery or an academic at UCL will increase your rankings far more than appearing on your friend’s Tumblr page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="Tips"></category><category term="SEO"></category><category term="Google"></category></entry></feed>